RG 022, Department of Economic and Community Development
Connecticut State Library
Department of Economic and Community Development records
1939-1997
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Economic and Community Development
13.75 cubic feet
The Department of Economic and Community Development is the state's agency for the development and implementation of policies, strategies and programs all of which are designed to enhance Connecticut's communities and business and housing environments.
RG022
Multiple
Historical Note
The Department of Economic and Community Development administers programs and policies to promote business, housing and community development. The agency combines housing, tourism, and economic growth. It began in 1937 with the Publicity Commission and in 1939 established as the Development Commission; in 1973 became the Connecticut Development Authority in the Department of Commerce; in 1979 a separate agency known as the Department of Economic Development; and in 1995 the agency became the Department of Economic and Community Development to consolidate the Department of Economic Development and the Department of Housing.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Records include: Connecticut Development Commission, lists of members, 1939-1971; minutes and attachments, January 1958-December 1969; a newsletter for members only, March 1941-February 1953; a printed bulletin, February 1940-June 1951; scrapbooks covering the peacetime draft in 1939-1940. Department of Commerce records pertaining to the development of an industrial park for New Britain, 1957-1973. There is also a report on a “Tourism Product Development Strategy,” 1997.
Arrangement
Series 1. Connecticut Development Commission, 1939-1971, 6.5 cubic feet
Accession: 1974-002, 4 cubic feet
Accession: 1989-075, 2.5 cubic feet
Series 2. Department of Commerce, 1957-1973, Accession: 1974-003, 7 cubic feet
Series 3. Tourism Division, 1997, Accession: 1999-175, 0.25 cubic feet
Related Material
RG 058 Research Commission
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Economic and Community Development; Connecticut Development Commission
Subjects:
Connecticut. Dept. of Economic and Community Development -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut Development Commission -- Records and correspondence; Community development -- Connecticut; Housing -- Connecticut; Tourism -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Contracts; Correspondence; Membership lists; Minutes; Newsletters; Reports; Testimonies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Connecticut Development Commission, 1939-1971; 6.5 cubic feet
  - Minutes and activities reports, 1958-1969; 1974-002; 25 volumes
    Minutes of meetings, with related agenda, correspondence, staff reports, budget requests, etc.
    - 1958 January-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1-25)
    - 1963-1966 April (Box 2, Folder 1-22)
    - 1966 May-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-15)
    - Attachments of official minutes, 1955-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16-24)
  - Lists of former members and chairmen, 1939-1971; 1974-002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Compilations of names, titles and addresses of Development Commission chairmen and members.
  - General Assembly file, 1969; 1974-002 (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
    Texts of statements before General Assembly committees on behalf of the Development Commission, with related papers.
  - Commission Doings, 1941 March-1953 February; 1974-002 (Box 4, Folder 6-18)
    A mimeographed, "confidential" newsletter reporting Development Commission activities.
  - Connecticut Progress, 1940 February-1951 June; 1974-002 (Box 4, Folder 19-21)
    Printed bulletin for public distribution.
  - Scrapbooks, 1939-1940; 1989-075; 5 volumes
    - 1940 October 1-1940 October 11, 1 volume (Volume Item 1)
    - 1940 October 11-1940 October 22, 1 volume (Volume Item 2)
    - 1939 October 23, 1940 October 22-1940 November 1, 1 volume (Volume Item 3)
    - 1940 November 8-1940 November 18, 1 volume (Volume Item 4)
    - 1940 December 1-1940 December 15, 1 volume (Volume Item 5)
- Series 2. Department of Commerce, 1957-1973; 1974-003; 7 cubic feet
  - New Britain Industrial Park, 1957-1973; 1974-003; 7 cubic feet
    Correspondence, agreements, contracts, reports, memoranda and related materials pertaining to the Development Commission's work on the Public Act No. 8 (May 1958) project.
    - Public Act No. 8 correspondence and reports, New Britain Industrial Park general correspondence, financial and budget files, miscellaneous and unfiled materials. (Box 1)
    - Classified ("Coded") files
      Subjects include planning, market analysis, renewal action program, quarterly reports, disposition agreements, contracts, change orders.
      Arranged by subject and thereunder unarranged.
      - Code 100 (Planning) - Code 306 (Market Analysis) (Box 2)
      - Code 320 (Renewal Action Program) - Code 501 & 540 (Quarterly Reports) (Box 3)
      - Code 501 & 540 (Quarterly Reports) - Code 507 (Disposition Agreements) (Box 4)
      - Code 507 (Disposition Agreements) (Box 5)
      - Code 507 (Disposition Agreements) - Code 551 (Contracts) (Box 6)
      - Code 551 (Contracts, Change Orders) (Box 7)
- Series 3. Tourism Division, 1997 January; 1999-175; 0.25 cubic feet
  - Connecticut Strategic Tourism Cluster Plan: Tourism Product Development Study, prepared by SRI International, 1997 January; 1 volume (Volume Envelope)